1. (a) Write an algorithm to find minimum and maximum value using divide and conquer and also drive it s complexity. 1, 1, 2, 3, 4, 8, 13, 21 examples. search? 20M Derive it's time complexity. Pro is     are     (P1,P2,P3,P4,PS,P6)=(1,2,4,4,7,2) and     weights     are  W1,W2,W3,W4,WS,W6) = (10,5,4,2,7,3). Find Max Pro t using Frac onal Knapsack. numbers. Draw the tree representa on to solve the subset sum problem given the  numbers set as {3,5,6,7,2} with sum = 15. Derive all the subsets. Comment on the  complexity of the algorithm. conquer and also drive it s complexity. 1, 1, 2, 3, 4, 8, 13, 21 examples. search? 20M Derive it's time complexity. Pro is     are     (P1,P2,P3,P4,PS,P6)=(1,2,4,4,7,2) and     weights     are  W1,W2,W3,W4,WS,W6) = (10,5,4,2,7,3). Find Max Pro t using Frac onal Knapsack. numbers. Draw the tree representa on to solve the subset sum problem given the  numbers set as {3,5,6,7,2} with sum = 15. Derive all the subsets. Comment on the  complexity of the algorithm.
b) To sort the given set of number using insertion sort and also show the resttit  of each pass. t  of each pass. 11, 7, 17, 3, 9, 29, 85, 9 > Explain How both can be used to solve Knapsack problem, CN alphabetical order. Analyze the best case, worst case and average case  complexities of quick sort. and-also derive its complexity. sum = 0; for( i = 0; i < n; 1++ )  for( j = 0; j < i; j++  sum++; t  of each pass. 11, 7, 17, 3, 9, 29, 85, 9 > Explain How both can be used to solve Knapsack problem, CN alphabetical order. Analyze the best case, worst case and average case  complexities of quick sort. and-also derive its complexity. sum = 0; for( i = 0; i < n; 1++ )  for( j = 0; j < i; j++  sum++;
2. (a) Find an optimal solution to the knapsack instance n = 7, m = Profit — {10, 5, 15, 7, 6, i8, 3} Weight = {2, 3, 5, 7, 1, 4, I} data. [ 10 7 5 9 1 2 3 ] Also write the Algorithm for it. tree. w= (5,7,10,12,15,18,20) and m=35. Find all possible subsets of w that sum to m. for all the three cases. notations. Profit — {10, 5, 15, 7, 6, i8, 3} Weight = {2, 3, 5, 7, 1, 4, I} data. [ 10 7 5 9 1 2 3 ] Also write the Algorithm for it. tree. w= (5,7,10,12,15,18,20) and m=35. Find all possible subsets of w that sum to m. for all the three cases. notations.
b) Explain optimal storage on tape with example. single source shortest path using greedy methods        - state space tree M = 35, W = (5, 7, 10, 12, 15, 18, 20). segment. 1=1;                              aNis, While(I<=n) X=X+I; 1=1+ 1;                   (11. rfriC max and min from given elements and explain. Derive the me complexity of this algorithm and compare it with a simple brute force  algorithm for nding max and min. For the following list of elements trace the recursive algorithm for nding max and min  programming. single source shortest path using greedy methods        - state space tree M = 35, W = (5, 7, 10, 12, 15, 18, 20). segment. 1=1;                              aNis, While(I<=n) X=X+I; 1=1+ 1;                   (11. rfriC max and min from given elements and explain. Derive the me complexity of this algorithm and compare it with a simple brute force  algorithm for nding max and min. For the following list of elements trace the recursive algorithm for nding max and min  programming.
3. (a) Find a minimum cost path from 1 to 9 in the given graph using dynamic programming. 3, and (11, 12, 13) = (5, 10, 3). to match follow txt [ = UNIVERSITY OF IviUMBAI pat [ ] = V 1.1 t	 n = 5, W = {2, 7, 8, 9, 15} M = 17 50, 31, 71, 38, 77, 81, 12, 33 g      d) Multi stage Graphs 22,12,-5,-8,15,60,17,31,47 state space tree for 4-queen problem. programming. 3, and (11, 12, 13) = (5, 10, 3). to match follow txt [ = UNIVERSITY OF IviUMBAI pat [ ] = V 1.1 t	 n = 5, W = {2, 7, 8, 9, 15} M = 17 50, 31, 71, 38, 77, 81, 12, 33 g      d) Multi stage Graphs 22,12,-5,-8,15,60,17,31,47 state space tree for 4-queen problem.
b) Find the path of travelling sales person problem of given graph. dl, d2, d3, d4) - (2, 1, 2, 1). Find feasible solutions, using job sequencing  with deadlines. fintikS r following using prims method. Merge sort and its complixity. Consider vertex 0 as source. 6 10-1—K.L'} 2 ■.___} ,--\  n=7, Profits(pl, p2„p7)       (3, 5, 20, 18, 1, 6, 30) Deadlines(dl,d2„d7) =    (1, 3, 4, 3, 2, 1,2}  algorithm design. search? 0.5,0.1,0.05} and q(0:3) = {0.15,0.1,0.05,0.05}. Compute and construct OBST for  above value using Dynamic Programming. T(n)=8T(n/2)+n2 dl, d2, d3, d4) - (2, 1, 2, 1). Find feasible solutions, using job sequencing  with deadlines. fintikS r following using prims method. Merge sort and its complixity. Consider vertex 0 as source. 6 10-1—K.L'} 2 ■.___} ,--\  n=7, Profits(pl, p2„p7)       (3, 5, 20, 18, 1, 6, 30) Deadlines(dl,d2„d7) =    (1, 3, 4, 3, 2, 1,2}  algorithm design. search? 0.5,0.1,0.05} and q(0:3) = {0.15,0.1,0.05,0.05}. Compute and construct OBST for  above value using Dynamic Programming. T(n)=8T(n/2)+n2
4. (a) To generate the Huffinan code for given set of frequencies. programming. 10M	 dr:6- W Solve Following Knapsack problem using dynamic approach. multistage graph. X = ababcde Y = bacadb Explain Backtracking with n-queen problem. Formulate Knapsack problem , Explain and differentiate between greedy knapsack  complexity. divide and conquer. Also derive its complexity. programming. 10M	 dr:6- W Solve Following Knapsack problem using dynamic approach. multistage graph. X = ababcde Y = bacadb Explain Backtracking with n-queen problem. Formulate Knapsack problem , Explain and differentiate between greedy knapsack  complexity. divide and conquer. Also derive its complexity.
b) To implement the knuth - Morris-Pratt, string matching algorithm. cc,	 z.....z< .,-2-,:z.:• A:'	 yz ";,• ..-  Item i	 Value vi .	 Weight wi -',... x AZ' S' - ,	 S                                                                 1 3 Explain Multistage graph with example. values using divide and conquer. Also drive its complexities. COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING" example of graph with 5 vertices. cc,	 z.....z< .,-2-,:z.:• A:'	 yz ";,• ..-  Item i	 Value vi .	 Weight wi -',... x AZ' S' - ,	 S                                                                 1 3 Explain Multistage graph with example. values using divide and conquer. Also drive its complexities. COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING" example of graph with 5 vertices.
5. (a) To find MST of following graph using prim's and kruskal's Algorithm. to tn, let n =6, m - 30, and w[1:6] - 15, 10, 12, 13, 15, 18) n.	 using dynamic programming with example. Solve following using 0/1 knapsack method Item (i)    Value (vi)    Weight(wi) p2,... p7)=(10,5, 15,7,6, 1 8,3), (w 1 ,N,v2,...w7)=(2,3,5,7, 1 ,4, 1 ) n=6, p=(18, 5, 9, 10, 12, 7) w=(7, 2, 3, 5, 3, 2) to tn, let n =6, m - 30, and w[1:6] - 15, 10, 12, 13, 15, 18) n.	 using dynamic programming with example. Solve following using 0/1 knapsack method Item (i)    Value (vi)    Weight(wi) p2,... p7)=(10,5, 15,7,6, 1 8,3), (w 1 ,N,v2,...w7)=(2,3,5,7, 1 ,4, 1 ) n=6, p=(18, 5, 9, 10, 12, 7) w=(7, 2, 3, 5, 3, 2)
5. (a) To find MST of following graph using prim's and kruskal's Algorithm. 4,.....,..„	 sq, 7,7‘• ,	 following problem. is less than standard coin weoz,Iit. To find the faulty coin in a list using proper     searching method. What will be the complexity of searching method. r     searching method. What will be the complexity of searching method. M=30      W=(5, 10, 12, 13, 15, 18} show its computing time is 0(n log n). lni al state                            Final State 4,.....,..„	 sq, 7,7‘• ,	 following problem. is less than standard coin weoz,Iit. To find the faulty coin in a list using proper     searching method. What will be the complexity of searching method. r     searching method. What will be the complexity of searching method. M=30      W=(5, 10, 12, 13, 15, 18} show its computing time is 0(n log n). lni al state                            Final State
b) Explain flow shop scheduling using sn5tabie data. s & n = 5, {131, P2, P, P4, P5} = {20, 15, 10, 5, 3} dr e1 d3, d4, d5} = {2, 2, 1, 3, 3} dynamic programming and prove that it is op mal. For the following graph determine the all pairs source shortest path for N =4. s & n = 5, {131, P2, P, P4, P5} = {20, 15, 10, 5, 3} dr e1 d3, d4, d5} = {2, 2, 1, 3, 3} dynamic programming and prove that it is op mal. For the following graph determine the all pairs source shortest path for N =4.
6. Write note on (Any two) i•-s--.,1--- -- 18 - -:- ics• --- ,. 2	 s. csks ---:.•	 7„/	 c- ,z•;-•:. complete? If so explain. following problem. n=4, w = {4, 5, 8, 9}, required sum = 9. i•-s--.,1--- -- 18 - -:- ics• --- ,. 2	 s. csks ---:.•	 7„/	 c- ,z•;-•:. complete? If so explain. following problem. n=4, w = {4, 5, 8, 9}, required sum = 9.
6. Write note on (Any two) 3	 i	 t	 A"4A.)$ z \„ ,:-:i.::-.t.S- -:  i(' 4	 10 -'s 7.2', :11-- -	 3 3	 i	 t	 A"4A.)$ z \„ ,:-:i.::-.t.S- -:  i(' 4	 10 -'s 7.2', :11-- -	 3
i) N-Queen Problem 10M array A = [2,3,5,6,7,8,9) and K = 15 Knapsack capacity=12. space tree. strings. X=ABACABB Y= BABCAB 10M array A = [2,3,5,6,7,8,9) and K = 15 Knapsack capacity=12. space tree. strings. X=ABACABB Y= BABCAB
ii) Randomized Algorithm is being affected?.	 10M is being affected?.	 10M
iii) Tries 10M  String x = ACBAED z,1” 10M  String x = ACBAED z,1”
iv) The 15 - puzzle problem. I.  (a) Define Q p , and El notations. To find the complexity of given recurrence relation.  ccS String y = ABCABE	 ccio Y = ABC ABE ccS String y = ABCABE	 ccio Y = ABC ABE
1) T(n) 4T(n/2) At? Let n=4, (Pi P2 P3 P4) =(100,10,15,27) and (di d2 d3 d4) (2,1,2,1) find feasible solution. At? Let n=4, (Pi P2 P3 P4) =(100,10,15,27) and (di d2 d3 d4) (2,1,2,1) find feasible solution.
ii) T(n) = 2T (n/2) +113 10M 10N1 ti 10M 10N1 ti
b) Implement the binary search, and derive its complexity.
a) Explain 0/1 knapsack problem using dynamic programming
b) Explain optimal storage on tapes and find the optimal order for given instance. 
3   (a) Let n - 4, (p1, p2, p3, p4) - (100, 10, 15 , 27) and
b) Find a minimum cost path from 3 to 2 in the given graph using dynamic 
4.  (a) Explain 8 Queen problem.
b) Explain sum of subset problem, Find all possible subsets of weight that suit 
5.  (a) Write an algorithm for Kanth-Morrie-Pratt (KMP). 
b) Explain the strassen's Matrix multiplication.
6. Write note on (any twn)H.
i) Randcirized Algorithms.
ii) Branch and bound strategy
iii) Huffman coding
iv) Rabin karp algorithm
1. (a) Which are the different methods of solving recurrences. Expl
b) Compare Greedy and dynamic programing approach for algori
2. (a) Explain the anlaysis of quick sort and apply the tt sort following
b) Write single source shortest path algorithm &apply the same for following.
3. (a) Explain string — ' finiat automata and apply the same technique
b) Com       & Kruskal's method for finding Minimum spanning Tree
a) Explain with example how divide and conquer stratergy is used in binary
b) Solve sum of subsets problem for following
N=6 W=13,5,7,8,9,15 )&M=20
a) Explain longest common subsequence problem with example.
b) What is backtracking method? How it is used in graph probtem?
6. Write short notes on (Any Four)
1) 8 queens problem
2) Job sequencing with deadlines
3) Flow shop scheduling
4) Multistage Graphs
5) A symptotic Notations IN
01. Answer Following Questions (Any Four)	
a) What is backtracking Approach. Explain how it is used in graph coloring.
b) Explain Randomized algorithm with example.
c) What is Knuth Morris Pratt Method of Pattern Matching? Give Examples..-, -;•-  
d) Explain in brief the concept of Multistage Graphs?	
e)   
Q2. A) Derive and comment on the complexity of Quick Sort algorithm;
N=4 items, capacity of knapsack M= 9 --7,„e..--- C,-'3 	
Q. r$ -...,
c.--	
4. cfr'...- Cs
1 	
2 *..'.- :J. s • 26•:''; E. `?.4,.;'.? 4    
Q3. A) What is sum of Subset problem? Write the Algorithm and solve following.	
b) Write the algorithm for finding strassens matrix multiplication and show how the complexity
Q4. A) What is Longest Commom subsequence Problem? Find LCS for following.	
C.:
4.•;\	
b) Explain binary search Tree? How to generate an optimal binary search tree.	
05. A) What is all pairs shortest path algorithm? Apply the same on following Graph.
b) Find MST of Following Graph using Priors and Ptisstes-Algorithm.
ra5 tcoli
Q6. Write Short Notes on (Any Three)
a) Optimal Storage on Tapes
b) 15 puzzle problem.
c) Binary Search and its complexity.
d) Problem of Multiplying Long Integers.
Q. I [a]    Explain the Strassen's matrix multiplication concept with an example.
b] Apply the quick sort algorithm to sort the list. E,X,A,M,P,L,E in 
Q.2 [a] Solve following problem of sum of subset and draw portion of state space 
b] What is single source shortest path algorithm. Write an algorithm to find 
Q.3 [a]     Prove that vertex cover problem is NP complete.
b]   Explain various string matching algorithms.
Q.4 [a]     Find the minimum cost path from s to t in the following figure using 
5.        3                               7
b] Describe the Travelling sales person problem and discuss how to solve it 
Q.5 [a] What is longest common subsequence problem? Find the LCS for the 
b] Write a short note on 8 queen problem, Write an algorithm for the same.
Q.6         Write a short note on(Any two)
1.Branch and Bound Strategy.
2.Algorithms to find minimum spanning tree. 
3.Recurrenses.
1. (a) Explain recurrences and various methods to solve recurrences.
b) Differentiate between P and NP.
c) Differentiate between Prims and Kruskals algorithm.
d) Explain Dynamic programming with example.
2. (a) Define Branch and Bound and Explain 15 Puzzle problem. 
b) Apply dijkstra's algorithm on the following graph. 
3. (a) Find Longest Common Subsequence for Following strings :
and 0/1 knapsack.
5. (a) Rewrite KMP algorithm and explain with example. 
b) Define chromatic number of graph. Explain Graph coloring algorithm.
6.       Write a short note on following (any 4) :
a) Master theorem
b) Rabin Karp algorithm
c) Steps for NP Completeness proofs
d) Assembly line scheduling problem I. (a) Explain 0, S2 and 0 Notations with the help of Graph. And represent the following  function using above notations.
i) T(n) = 3n + 2
ii) T(n) = 10n2 + 2n + 1
b) Explain 0/1 Knapsack Problem with example.
2. (a) Write an algorithm of sum of subsets. Solve folibwing problem and draw portion of 
b) Explain longest common subsequence with example.
3. (a) Explain all pair shortest path algorithm with suitable example. 
b) Explain different string matching algorithms.
4. (a) Write a Min Max function to find minimum and maximum value from given set of 
b) Comment on any two modules of computation.
5. (a) "lb find I)ijkstra's shortest path from vertex 1 to vertex 4 for following graph.
b) Explain flow shop scheduling with example.
6. 'Write note on :— (any two)
a) Job sequencing with deadlines
b) Randomized Algorithm
c) The 15 Puzzle Problem
d) N-Queen Problem.
1. (a) Write abstract algorithm for greedy design method.
b) Which are different factors considered for sorting elements.
c) Explain flow shop scheduling technique.
d) Explain three cases of master theorem.
2. (a) Write and explain sum of subset algorithm for
b) Explain randomized version of Quick sort and derive its complexity
3. (a) Implement the bubble sort Algorithm and derive its best case and worst case 
b) Find the Huffman code for the following message.
4. (a) What is IIamiltonian cycle ? Write an algorithm to find all Hamiltonian cycles.   (b) Suppose you are given n numbi.tr of coins, in that one coin is faulty, its weight      is less than standard coin weoz,Iit. To find the faulty coin in a list using proper     searching method. What will be the complexity of searching method.
b) Suppose you are given n numbi.tr of coins, in that one coin is faulty, its weight      is less than standard coin weoz,Iit. To find the faulty coin in a list using proper     searching method. What will be the complexity of searching method.
5. (a) Explain Job segue:icing with deadliner for the given instance. 
b) Explain naive string matching algorithm with example.
6. Write note on : (any two)
a) Rabin karp algorithm
b) 15-puzzle problem
c) Travelling sales person problem
d) Strassen's matrix multiplication.
Q1.  a) Explain the asymptotic notatinos.
b) Write an algorithm to find minimum and maximum value using divide and conquer 
Q2. a) Explain the concept of multiplying long integers using divide and conquer. 
b) Son the following numbers using Quick Sort. Also derive the time complexity 
of Quick Sort.
Q3. a) Solve the following Job sequencing with deadlines problem 
b) Explain different string matching algorithms.
Q4. a) Find the Minimum Spanning Tree of the following graph using itruskalls algorithm
b) Explain flow shop schedulingIttifli example.
Q5. a) Write an algorithm for sum of subsets. Solve the following problem. 
b) Find the shortest path from source vertex A using Dijkstra's algorithm
Q6. Write note on (any two):
a) Strassen's matrix multiplication.
b) 8-Queen problem.
5     c) Graph coloring
d) 15-puzzle problem.
Q. 1      Answer any four
a) Write an algorithm for finding maximum and minimum number from given set
b) Write the algorithm and derived the complexity of Binary Search algorithm.
c) Explain masters method with example
d) Write a note on flow shop scheduling
e) Compare divide and conquer, dynamic programming and Backtracking approache used for 
Q. 2  a) Write and explain string matching with finite automata with an example
b) Explain how branch and bound strategy can be used in 15 puzzle problem.
Q. 3  a) What is 0/1 knapsack and fractional knapsack problem.
1           18              3
2           25              5
3           27              4
4           10              3
5           15              6
b) Explain insertion sort and derive its complexity
Q. 4  a) What is a binary search tree? How to generate optimal binary search tree
b) What is a longest common subsequence problem? Find LCS for following string X = ACB AED 
Q. 5  a) Explain Job Sequencing with deadlines.
b) Explain prims algorithm and find minimum spanning tree for the following graph.
Q.6   Write short notes (any three):-
Q.6   Write short notes (any three):-
a) Problem of multiplying Long Integers       b) Strassen's matrix multiplication
b) Strassen's matrix multiplication
c) Knuth Morris Pratt's Pattern matching      d) Multi stage Graphs
Q.1 Answer the following
a. Write the difference between greedy method and dynamic programming.
b. Explain the general procedure of divide and conquer method.
c. Determine the frequency counts for all statements in the following algorithm 
d. What is backtracking Approach? Explain how it is used in Graph Coloring
Q.2.a. Explain with example how divide and conquer strategy is used in binary 
b. Solve sum of subsets problem for following
N=6 W={3,5,7,8,9,15} & M =20 Also write the Algorithm for it.
Q.3 a. Obtain the solution to knapsack problem by Greedy method n=7,m=15 (pl,
b. Sort the list of the elements 10,5,7,6,1,4,8,3,2,9 using merge sort algorithm and 
Q. 4.a. Explain different string matching algorithms.
b. What do you understand by NP Complete? Explain Is Subset sum problem NP 
Q. 5.a. Write a detailednote on Hamiltonian cycles.
b. Explain how backtracking is used for solving n- queens problem. Show the state 
Q.6 Write Short Note on (any 2)
a. Job sequencing with deadlines
b. 8 queens problem
c. Longest common subsequence
Q.1   a. Consider     the   instance   of   knapsack  problem    where    n=6,   M=15,
b. Compute worst case complexity of following program segment 
c.   Write Quicksort algorithm using Divide and Conquer approach. Derive its complexity 
Q.2   a.   Explain Divide and Conquer approach. Write a recursive algorithm to determine the
and determine how many comparisons have been made.
Q.3   a.   What is op mal binary search tree? Let n = 3 and {al,a2,a3} ={do,if,while}. Let p(1:3)
b. Solve 8 puzzle problem by Branch and Bound. Draw State space tree.
1      3                                1  2   3
6                                   5  8   6
7   8  4                                7  4
Q.4        Write and Explain the algorithm to compute all pair source shortest path using
Q.5 a. Write an algorithm to determine the sum of subsets for a given Sum and a Set of
Q.5 b. An algorithm takes 0.5ms for input size 100. How long will it take for an input size 500.
If the running me is following
1) Linear 2) Quadra c 3) Cubic 4) Jn 5) nlog2n
Q.6 A  Explain the idea behind backtracking? Write an algorithm for N-queen problem. Draw
b  What is LCS? Find LCS for string S = "ABAZDC" and 1". "BACBAD"
Q.1)  Solve any 4
1) Derive the complexity of quick sort for best case and worst case.
2) What is asymptotic analysis? Define Big 0, Omega and Theta 
3) Write an algorithm to find all pairs shortest path using dynamic 
4) Write a note on "Optimal Storage on Tapes".
5) Define master theorem. Solve the following using master method. 
Q.2. A) Write an algorithm for finding minimum and maximum using 
B) Write Kruskal's algorithm and show its working by taking suitable 
Q.3. A) Solve fractional knapsack problem for the following.
B) Write an algorithm for Knuth Morris Pratt (KMP) pattern matching.
Q.4. A) Write an algorithm to solve N Queens problem. Show its working 
B) Write an algorithm to solve sum of subset problem and solve the 
Q.S. A) Prove that Vertex Cover problem is NP Complete.
B) Find the longest common subsequence for the following two 
Q.6)  Write short note on any 2.
a) Assembly Line,Scheduling
b) Job Sequencing with Deadlines
c) 15 Puzzle Problem (d) P, NP and NPC Classes
1. (a) Write an algorithm to find minimum and maximum value using divide and
b) To sort the given set of number using insertion sort and also show the resttit  of each pass.
2. (a) Find an optimal solution to the knapsack instance n = 7, m =
b) Explain optimal storage on tape with example.
3. (a) Find a minimum cost path from 1 to 9 in the given graph using dynamic
b) Find the path of travelling sales person problem of given graph.
4. (a) To generate the Huffinan code for given set of frequencies.
b) To implement the knuth - Morris-Pratt, string matching algorithm.
5. (a) To find MST of following graph using prim's and kruskal's Algorithm.
5. (a) To find MST of following graph using prim's and kruskal's Algorithm.
b) Explain flow shop scheduling using sn5tabie data.
6. Write note on (Any two)
6. Write note on (Any two)
i) N-Queen Problem
ii) Randomized Algorithm
iii) Tries
iv) The 15 - puzzle problem. I.  (a) Define Q p , and El notations. To find the complexity of given recurrence relation. 
1) T(n) 4T(n/2)
ii) T(n) = 2T (n/2) +113
b) Implement the binary search, and derive its complexity.
a) Explain 0/1 knapsack problem using dynamic programming
b) Explain optimal storage on tapes and find the optimal order for given instance. 
3   (a) Let n - 4, (p1, p2, p3, p4) - (100, 10, 15 , 27) and
b) Find a minimum cost path from 3 to 2 in the given graph using dynamic 
4.  (a) Explain 8 Queen problem.
b) Explain sum of subset problem, Find all possible subsets of weight that suit 
5.  (a) Write an algorithm for Kanth-Morrie-Pratt (KMP). 
b) Explain the strassen's Matrix multiplication.
6. Write note on (any twn)H.
i) Randcirized Algorithms.
ii) Branch and bound strategy
iii) Huffman coding
iv) Rabin karp algorithm
1. (a) Which are the different methods of solving recurrences. Expl
b) Compare Greedy and dynamic programing approach for algori
2. (a) Explain the anlaysis of quick sort and apply the tt sort following
b) Write single source shortest path algorithm &apply the same for following.
3. (a) Explain string — ' finiat automata and apply the same technique
b) Com       & Kruskal's method for finding Minimum spanning Tree
a) Explain with example how divide and conquer stratergy is used in binary
b) Solve sum of subsets problem for following
N=6 W=13,5,7,8,9,15 )&M=20
a) Explain longest common subsequence problem with example.
b) What is backtracking method? How it is used in graph probtem?
6. Write short notes on (Any Four)
1) 8 queens problem
2) Job sequencing with deadlines
3) Flow shop scheduling
4) Multistage Graphs
5) A symptotic Notations IN
01. Answer Following Questions (Any Four)	
a) What is backtracking Approach. Explain how it is used in graph coloring.
b) Explain Randomized algorithm with example.
c) What is Knuth Morris Pratt Method of Pattern Matching? Give Examples..-, -;•-  
d) Explain in brief the concept of Multistage Graphs?	
e)   
Q2. A) Derive and comment on the complexity of Quick Sort algorithm;
N=4 items, capacity of knapsack M= 9 --7,„e..--- C,-'3 	
Q. r$ -...,
c.--	
4. cfr'...- Cs
1 	
2 *..'.- :J. s • 26•:''; E. `?.4,.;'.? 4    
Q3. A) What is sum of Subset problem? Write the Algorithm and solve following.	
b) Write the algorithm for finding strassens matrix multiplication and show how the complexity
Q4. A) What is Longest Commom subsequence Problem? Find LCS for following.	
C.:
4.•;\	
b) Explain binary search Tree? How to generate an optimal binary search tree.	
05. A) What is all pairs shortest path algorithm? Apply the same on following Graph.
b) Find MST of Following Graph using Priors and Ptisstes-Algorithm.
ra5 tcoli
Q6. Write Short Notes on (Any Three)
a) Optimal Storage on Tapes
b) 15 puzzle problem.
c) Binary Search and its complexity.
d) Problem of Multiplying Long Integers.
Q. I [a]    Explain the Strassen's matrix multiplication concept with an example.
b] Apply the quick sort algorithm to sort the list. E,X,A,M,P,L,E in 
Q.2 [a] Solve following problem of sum of subset and draw portion of state space 
b] What is single source shortest path algorithm. Write an algorithm to find 
Q.3 [a]     Prove that vertex cover problem is NP complete.
b]   Explain various string matching algorithms.
Q.4 [a]     Find the minimum cost path from s to t in the following figure using 
5.        3                               7
b] Describe the Travelling sales person problem and discuss how to solve it 
Q.5 [a] What is longest common subsequence problem? Find the LCS for the 
b] Write a short note on 8 queen problem, Write an algorithm for the same.
Q.6         Write a short note on(Any two)
1.Branch and Bound Strategy.
2.Algorithms to find minimum spanning tree. 
3.Recurrenses.
1. (a) Explain recurrences and various methods to solve recurrences.
b) Differentiate between P and NP.
c) Differentiate between Prims and Kruskals algorithm.
d) Explain Dynamic programming with example.
2. (a) Define Branch and Bound and Explain 15 Puzzle problem. 
b) Apply dijkstra's algorithm on the following graph. 
3. (a) Find Longest Common Subsequence for Following strings :
and 0/1 knapsack.
5. (a) Rewrite KMP algorithm and explain with example. 
b) Define chromatic number of graph. Explain Graph coloring algorithm.
6.       Write a short note on following (any 4) :
a) Master theorem
b) Rabin Karp algorithm
c) Steps for NP Completeness proofs
d) Assembly line scheduling problem I. (a) Explain 0, S2 and 0 Notations with the help of Graph. And represent the following  function using above notations.
i) T(n) = 3n + 2
ii) T(n) = 10n2 + 2n + 1
b) Explain 0/1 Knapsack Problem with example.
2. (a) Write an algorithm of sum of subsets. Solve folibwing problem and draw portion of 
b) Explain longest common subsequence with example.
3. (a) Explain all pair shortest path algorithm with suitable example. 
b) Explain different string matching algorithms.
4. (a) Write a Min Max function to find minimum and maximum value from given set of 
b) Comment on any two modules of computation.
5. (a) "lb find I)ijkstra's shortest path from vertex 1 to vertex 4 for following graph.
b) Explain flow shop scheduling with example.
6. 'Write note on :— (any two)
a) Job sequencing with deadlines
b) Randomized Algorithm
c) The 15 Puzzle Problem
d) N-Queen Problem.
1. (a) Write abstract algorithm for greedy design method.
b) Which are different factors considered for sorting elements.
c) Explain flow shop scheduling technique.
d) Explain three cases of master theorem.
2. (a) Write and explain sum of subset algorithm for
b) Explain randomized version of Quick sort and derive its complexity
3. (a) Implement the bubble sort Algorithm and derive its best case and worst case 
b) Find the Huffman code for the following message.
4. (a) What is IIamiltonian cycle ? Write an algorithm to find all Hamiltonian cycles.   (b) Suppose you are given n numbi.tr of coins, in that one coin is faulty, its weight      is less than standard coin weoz,Iit. To find the faulty coin in a list using proper     searching method. What will be the complexity of searching method.
b) Suppose you are given n numbi.tr of coins, in that one coin is faulty, its weight      is less than standard coin weoz,Iit. To find the faulty coin in a list using proper     searching method. What will be the complexity of searching method.
5. (a) Explain Job segue:icing with deadliner for the given instance. 
b) Explain naive string matching algorithm with example.
6. Write note on : (any two)
a) Rabin karp algorithm
b) 15-puzzle problem
c) Travelling sales person problem
d) Strassen's matrix multiplication.
Q1.  a) Explain the asymptotic notatinos.
b) Write an algorithm to find minimum and maximum value using divide and conquer 
Q2. a) Explain the concept of multiplying long integers using divide and conquer. 
b) Son the following numbers using Quick Sort. Also derive the time complexity 
of Quick Sort.
Q3. a) Solve the following Job sequencing with deadlines problem 
b) Explain different string matching algorithms.
Q4. a) Find the Minimum Spanning Tree of the following graph using itruskalls algorithm
b) Explain flow shop schedulingIttifli example.
Q5. a) Write an algorithm for sum of subsets. Solve the following problem. 
b) Find the shortest path from source vertex A using Dijkstra's algorithm
Q6. Write note on (any two):
a) Strassen's matrix multiplication.
b) 8-Queen problem.
5     c) Graph coloring
d) 15-puzzle problem.
Q. 1      Answer any four
a) Write an algorithm for finding maximum and minimum number from given set
b) Write the algorithm and derived the complexity of Binary Search algorithm.
c) Explain masters method with example
d) Write a note on flow shop scheduling
e) Compare divide and conquer, dynamic programming and Backtracking approache used for 
Q. 2  a) Write and explain string matching with finite automata with an example
b) Explain how branch and bound strategy can be used in 15 puzzle problem.
Q. 3  a) What is 0/1 knapsack and fractional knapsack problem.
1           18              3
2           25              5
3           27              4
4           10              3
5           15              6
b) Explain insertion sort and derive its complexity
Q. 4  a) What is a binary search tree? How to generate optimal binary search tree
b) What is a longest common subsequence problem? Find LCS for following string X = ACB AED 
Q. 5  a) Explain Job Sequencing with deadlines.
b) Explain prims algorithm and find minimum spanning tree for the following graph.
Q.6   Write short notes (any three):-
Q.6   Write short notes (any three):-
a) Problem of multiplying Long Integers       b) Strassen's matrix multiplication
b) Strassen's matrix multiplication
c) Knuth Morris Pratt's Pattern matching      d) Multi stage Graphs
Q.1 Answer the following
a. Write the difference between greedy method and dynamic programming.
b. Explain the general procedure of divide and conquer method.
c. Determine the frequency counts for all statements in the following algorithm 
d. What is backtracking Approach? Explain how it is used in Graph Coloring
Q.2.a. Explain with example how divide and conquer strategy is used in binary 
b. Solve sum of subsets problem for following
N=6 W={3,5,7,8,9,15} & M =20 Also write the Algorithm for it.
Q.3 a. Obtain the solution to knapsack problem by Greedy method n=7,m=15 (pl,
b. Sort the list of the elements 10,5,7,6,1,4,8,3,2,9 using merge sort algorithm and 
Q. 4.a. Explain different string matching algorithms.
b. What do you understand by NP Complete? Explain Is Subset sum problem NP 
Q. 5.a. Write a detailednote on Hamiltonian cycles.
b. Explain how backtracking is used for solving n- queens problem. Show the state 
Q.6 Write Short Note on (any 2)
a. Job sequencing with deadlines
b. 8 queens problem
c. Longest common subsequence
Q.1   a. Consider     the   instance   of   knapsack  problem    where    n=6,   M=15,
b. Compute worst case complexity of following program segment 
c.   Write Quicksort algorithm using Divide and Conquer approach. Derive its complexity 
Q.2   a.   Explain Divide and Conquer approach. Write a recursive algorithm to determine the
and determine how many comparisons have been made.
Q.3   a.   What is op mal binary search tree? Let n = 3 and {al,a2,a3} ={do,if,while}. Let p(1:3)
b. Solve 8 puzzle problem by Branch and Bound. Draw State space tree.
1      3                                1  2   3
6                                   5  8   6
7   8  4                                7  4
Q.4        Write and Explain the algorithm to compute all pair source shortest path using
Q.5 a. Write an algorithm to determine the sum of subsets for a given Sum and a Set of
Q.5 b. An algorithm takes 0.5ms for input size 100. How long will it take for an input size 500.
If the running me is following
1) Linear 2) Quadra c 3) Cubic 4) Jn 5) nlog2n
Q.6 A  Explain the idea behind backtracking? Write an algorithm for N-queen problem. Draw
b  What is LCS? Find LCS for string S = "ABAZDC" and 1". "BACBAD"
Q.1)  Solve any 4
1) Derive the complexity of quick sort for best case and worst case.
2) What is asymptotic analysis? Define Big 0, Omega and Theta 
3) Write an algorithm to find all pairs shortest path using dynamic 
4) Write a note on "Optimal Storage on Tapes".
5) Define master theorem. Solve the following using master method. 
Q.2. A) Write an algorithm for finding minimum and maximum using 
B) Write Kruskal's algorithm and show its working by taking suitable 
Q.3. A) Solve fractional knapsack problem for the following.
B) Write an algorithm for Knuth Morris Pratt (KMP) pattern matching.
Q.4. A) Write an algorithm to solve N Queens problem. Show its working 
B) Write an algorithm to solve sum of subset problem and solve the 
Q.S. A) Prove that Vertex Cover problem is NP Complete.
B) Find the longest common subsequence for the following two 
Q.6)  Write short note on any 2.
a) Assembly Line,Scheduling
b) Job Sequencing with Deadlines
c) 15 Puzzle Problem 
d) P, NP and NPC Classes
